* Internet.bs
    * [Live Chat](javascript:%24zopim.livechat.window.show(); "Live Chat")

Login

Login _\*_

Password _\*_

Create account

Email _\*_

Password _\*_

Confirm password _\*_

   I agree to the [Account Terms and Conditions](https://internetbs.net/en/termsandconditions.html) and I am 16 years old or over _\*_

   I'd love Internet.bs to contact me about new products and promotions

   Remember me

##### Fill using template

Load       Delete

|  
or  
|

    * [Live Chat](javascript:%24zopim.livechat.window.show(); "Live Chat")

new

Privacy Policy
--------------

Last Updated: 17 Aug 2022

Content
-------

1. [General Information](#A)
    1. [Controller](#A)
    2. [Data Protection Officer](#A2)
    3. [Your rights](#A3)
    4. [Legal Bases for Processing Your Data](#A4)
    5. [Retention Periods](#A5)
    6. [Children](#A6)
    7. [Recipients of Data, Third-Country Transfers, Linked Third-Party Websites](#A7)
    8. [Data Security](#A8)
    9. [Automated Decision Making](#A9)
    10. [Data processing when you are based in the EU/EEA](#A10)
2. [Collection and Processing of your Personal Data when using our Website](#B)
    1. [Technical Provision of the Website, Hosting](#B)
    2. [Security and Performance](#B2)
        1. [Google reCAPTCHA](#B2)
        2. [CloudFlare](#B2b)
    3. [Other plugins and embedded third-party content](#B3)
        1. [Google Fonts](#B3)
        2. [Surveys/Polls](#B3b)
    4. [Newsletter](#B4)
    5. [Commercial Services](#B5)
        1. [Account Registration](#B5)
        2. [Log-In Using Third-Party Providers](#B5b)
        3. [Payment](#B5c)
        4. [Direct Marketing](#B5d)
        5. [Domain Query (Whois)](#B5e)
    6. [Contact, Live Chat](#B6)
3. [Statistics, Web-Analytics, Advertising based on Tracking and Retargeting – Use of Cookies](#C)
    1. [Web-Analytics, Statistics](#C1)
        1. [Google Analytics](#C1a)
        2. [Hotjar](#C2b)
    2. [Advertising based on Tracking and Retargeting](#C2)
        1. [Facebook Pixel](#C2a)

Privacy Policy
--------------

Thank you for your interest in our website. The protection of your personal data (hereinafter referred to as “data”) is a major and very important concern for us. Below, we would like to inform you in detail about which data is collected during your visit to our website and your use of our offers there, and how we subsequently process or use this data.

Please note that this Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time due to the implementation of new technologies or legislative changes. We will notify you of these changes as appropriate, and we will, of course, duly take your interests into account when making changes.

Please also see our separate Domain Name Registration Privacy Policy regarding the processing of personal data for registration of domain names [https://iwantmyname.com/terms#use-personal-information](https://iwantmyname.com/terms#use-personal-information). The purpose of that policy is to inform you about how personal data is processed when a domain is registered.

A. General Information
----------------------

#### 1\. Controller

The controllers are Internet Domain Service BS Corp., Ocean Cenre, Montagu Foreshore, East Bay Street Nassau, New Providence, The Bahamas, and CentralNic Group PLC, a company registered in England & Wales with Registration Number 08576358, Address: 4th Floor, Saddlers House, 44 Gutter Lane, London, EC2V 6BR. E-mail:[\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Within the CentralNic group certain departments and tasks are shared between the individual group companies. The controllers shall jointly determine the purpose and means of processing. This is described below and in our Privacy Policy regarding the processing of personal data for registration of domain names. Hereinafter, the use of the name "CentralNic" refers to the joint controllers collectively, unless one or more entities are expressly mentioned. If you have any questions or claims regarding data protection, you can contact any group company mentioned in this privacy policy and our website.

The EU-GDPR Representative of controllers not established in the EU can be reached at Key-Systems GmbH, Im Oberen Werk 1, 66386 St. Ingbert, Germany, [\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). The Representative serves as a point of contact for data subjects on all issues related to the processing of personal data and for the purpose of ensuring compliance with the EU GDPR.

#### 2\. Data Protection Officer

Attn: Privacy Officer  
Internet Domain Service BS Corp.  
Ocean Centre  
Montagu Foreshore, East Bay Street, Nassau  
New Providence, The Bahamas  
P.O. Box SS-19084  
e-mail: [\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or about data protection in general, please contact our data protection officer by e-mail at [\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

The Data Privacy Officer of CentralNic Group PLC can be contacted at Data Privacy Officer, CentralNic Group PLC, 4th Floor, Saddlers House, 44 Gutter Lane, London, EC2V 6BR or by e-mail at [\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### 3\. Your rights

You may assert the following rights free of charge against any person responsible for the processing of your personal data:

* Right to withdraw your consent.
* Right of access: You may request access to your personal information that we process.
* Right to object: You have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time for reasons relating to your special situation. The controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override the interests, rights, and freedoms of the data subject or for the establishment, exercise, or defence of legal claims. The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of the log files is absolutely necessary for the operation of the website.
* Right to rectification: If the information concerning you is not (or is no longer) accurate, you may request a rectification. If your data is incomplete, you may request their completion.
* Right to erasure: You can request the erasure of your personal data.
* Right to restriction of processing: you have the right to request a restriction on the processing of your personal data.
* Right to data portability: you have the right to receive or have a third party receive the data that we process automatically on the basis of your consent or in the performance of a contract. This right only applies to (electronically) data processing carried out by automated means whereat the processing is either based on your consent or on a contract pursuant and that you have us provided with the data yourself. Therefore, the right is not applicable to the log files collected via our website.

For the assertion of claims, please contact the controller or data protection officer (find contact details above). Should you wish to contact us by e-mail, please use an address used to access our system so that we can identify you.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint about the controller's processing of your personal data with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection.

#### 4\. Legal Bases for Processing Your Data

In principle, we only process data when a legal basis is available. We specify the legal basis in the segments about data processing, but in general, we are permitted to process your personal data if one of the following conditions applies:

* The data subject’s consent for the processing of personal data.
* Processing personal data as a necessity for the fulfilment of a contract in return for payment or free of charge. This shall also apply to processing operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures.
* The processing is necessary for the fulfilment of a legal obligation to which we are subject.
* The processing is necessary to safeguard a legitimate interest of our company or a third party and if the interests, fundamental rights, and fundamental freedoms of the data subject do not outweigh the above-mentioned interests.

#### 5\. Retention Periods

The data processed by us will be erased or their processing will be restricted in compliance with the legal regulations. Unless expressly stated in the context of this Privacy Policy, we will erase data stored by us as soon as it is no longer required for their intended purpose. Data will only be retained beyond the time it is no longer needed for its intended purpose if this is necessary for other legally permissible purposes or if the data must be retained longer due to statutory retention obligations. In these cases, processing is restricted, i.e. blocked, and the data are not processed for other purposes. For example, a statutory retention obligation exists, due to documentation obligations under tax and corporate law.

#### 6\. Children

Our website is not intended for children under the age of 16.

#### 7\. Recipients of Data, Third-Country Transfers, Linked Third-Party Websites

We do use external service providers for the processing of your data and hereby want to inform you about the third parties and processors we transfer data to. We use various third-party services on our website. These have different purposes, which we will discuss in more detail in the individual descriptions. These services serve to make our website functional, secure, and visually appealing, as well as to optimise its content on an ongoing basis. In general, we transfer data to the following categories of recipients:

Billing service providers, print- and postal providers, insurances, telecommunications provider, insurance broker and subject matter experts for assessing and regulating of claims, public authorities, provided a justified request, credit institutions and payment service providers, external accountant, auditors, Host Providers and other service providers for this website, and legal counsel.

In the case of cross border transfer (transfer to a third country or to an international organisation) we do inform you separately about the recipient, and the correspondent legal basis. However, in the case that your data is transferred outside of the European Union either to Controllers or Processors, the transfer is justified by the Standard Contractual Clauses according to the Annex of the Commission Decision 2010/87/EU regarding the Directive 95/46/EC, or by other safeguards.

As far as processors are being used, they are bound by our instructions under data protection law. These service providers are our contractors and assist with processing of your personal data, for example, to provide this website. These contractors have been carefully selected and authorised and are regularly monitored. The authorisations are based on agreements for processing. The processors do not perform any independent processing for their own purposes.

Our website may contain links to third-party websites. If you follow a link to one of these websites, we point out to you that these offers have their own data protection policies and that we are not the controllers for the processing of your data on these websites. Please review each privacy policy before disclosing personal information to those controllers.

#### 8\. Data Security

We apply technical and organisational security measures to protect personal data that is collected, in particular against accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction or against the attack of unauthorised persons. Our security measures are continuously improved in line with technological developments. To protect your data in transit we use encryption technologies (TLS).

#### 9\. Automated Decision Making

We do not use automated decision making, including profiling.

#### 10\. Data processing when you are based in the EU/EEA, EU-Representative

When you are based in the EU/EEA, we only process data when a legal basis is available as mentioned above. For EU/EEA related data processing, in general, the following legal bases shall apply to the processing of data under our responsibility.

* The data subject’s consent for the processing of personal data, Article 6 (1) (a), Article 7 GDPR.
* Processing personal data as a necessity for the fulfilment (performance) of a contract in return for payment or free of charge, Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR. This shall also apply to processing operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures.
* The processing is necessary for the fulfilment of a legal obligation to which we are subject, Article 6 (1) (c) GDPR.
* The processing is necessary to safeguard a legitimate interest of our company or a third party and if the interests, fundamental rights, and fundamental freedoms of the data subject do not outweigh the above-mentioned interests, Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR.

Subject to the member states’ legal requirements, you may be entitled to assert the following rights: Right of access by the data subject, Article 15 GDPR, Right to rectification, Article 16 GDPR, Right to erasure (‘right to be forgotten’), Article 17 GDPR, Right to restriction of processing, Article 18 GDPR, Right to data portability, Article 20 GDPR, Right to object, Article 21 GDPR, Right to withdraw consent, Article 7 (3) GDPR, Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, Article 77 GDPR.

The EU-GDPR Representative of controllers not established in the EU can be reached at Key-Systems GmbH, Im Oberen Werk 1, 66386 St. Ingbert, Germany, [\[email protected\]](https://internetbs.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). The Representative serves as a point of contact for data subjects on all issues related to the processing of personal data and for the purpose of ensuring compliance with the EU GDPR.

B. Collection and Processing of your Personal Data when using our Website
-------------------------------------------------------------------------

#### 1\. Technical Provision of the Website, Hosting

For the informational use of our website, you generally do not need to actively provide personal data. Each time you use the internet, your browser is transmitting certain information which we store in so-called log files, such as:

* Date and time of retrieval of one of our web pages.
* your IP address.
* host name of the connecting device.
* the website from which our website was accessed.
* following websites that were accessed via our website.
* the page visited on our website.
* the transmitted amount of data and the access status (file transmission, file not found etc.).
* your browser type and version used.
* the operating system used.

The temporary storage of the data is necessary for the course of a website visit to enable delivery of the website. Further storage of the log files takes place in order to ensure the functionality of the website and the security of the information technology systems (especially to prevent abusive attacks, so-called DDoS attacks). Unless otherwise specified, your IP address will be shortened as soon as possible so that it is no longer possible to identify you. The legal basis for the temporary storage is to provide you with our website for the fulfilment of a contract or to process operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures. The legal basis for further storage with a shortened IP address is our legitimate interest to protect our information technology systems. A personal evaluation of the data, in particular for marketing purposes, does not take place without prior consent.

To operate this website, we use Amazon Web Services (“AWS”) of Amazon Inc., 410 Terry Avenue North, Seattle WA 98109, United States, a hosting provider to process meta and communication data of our website users, on our behalf and based on our legitimate interests in an efficient and secure provision of this website.

#### 2\. Security and Performance

##### a. Google reCAPTCHA

We use Google reCAPTCHA to prevent automatic programs/bots from using our contact form. This increases the security of our website and avoids SPAM. This is also our legitimate interest and fulfils our legal obligation.

The collected data is hardware and software information, e.g. device and application data as well as the results of security checks. This data is transmitted to Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. The data will not be used for personalised advertising.

Further information can be found in Google's privacy policy at [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Further documentation can be found at [https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/](https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/) and at [https://www.google.com/recaptcha/admin/create](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/admin/create).

##### b. CloudFlare

This website uses CloudFlare (Service Provider: Cloudflare Inc., 101 Townsend Street, San Francisco, California 94107, USA) to safeguard our internet presence and optimise loading times.

When you load our website, your requests are routed by the CloudFlare Server and statistical data about your visit is being collected and stored on a cookie on your device. This data includes your IP-address, accessed websites, type and version of your browser, your operating system, the referrer-URL (the site, from where you reached us), the length of your stay and the frequency of requests on our pages.

CloudFlare guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses to maintain the EU level of data protection.

The legal basis is our legitimate interest in safeguarding and optimizing the functionality of our website.

For further details, please see [http://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy).

#### 3\. Other plugins and embedded third-party content

##### a. Google Fonts

This website uses Google Fonts of Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (Holding Company: Google LLC 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). Google Fonts is an interactive register with over 800 fonts, that Google provides free of charge.

Google Fonts is an important tool, to keep the high quality of our website. With Google Fonts we can use fonts without having to upload them to our servers. These fonts are automatically optimised for the web and there save data traffic and result in quicker loading times.

Google Fonts supports all established browsers and works reliantly on most mobile devices.

The legal basis is formed by our legitimate interests in the efficient and secure provision of the website.

Google Fonts does not set any cookies on your device. The data is requested via the google-domains fonts.googleapis.com and fonts.gstatic.com. According to Google, these requests are processed separately from other services Google provides. This includes your Google account, if you have one.

Google captures the usage of CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) as well as the fonts used and saves this data securely. Google stores CSS-requests for a day on their servers, which mostly are located outside of the EU. Insofar as Google Ireland Limited transfers personal data to the US parent company Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, Google guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses to maintain the EU level of data protection. Google’s goal is to improve loading time of websites by caching the fonts once and then using them again on any other website that uses Google Fonts. Next to this data, every Google Fonts request also automatically transmits data like your IP-address, language settings, screen resolution, name, and version of your browser to the Google Servers. This is necessary to ensure a correct graphical display.

##### b. Surveys/Polls

On our website you can participate in surveys. When you voluntarily participate in this survey, information about the device and application you use to participate in the survey is processed. This includes IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, duration of visit, page views and navigation paths of the website or similar information.

For this purpose, we use:

* the service of Hotjar Inc., Level 2, St Julian's Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julian's STJ 1000, Malta. Further information about data processing can be found in the privacy policy at [https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy)
* the service of SurveyMonkey Europe UC, 2 Shelbourne Buildings, Second Floor, Shelbourne Road, Dublin 4, Ireland. Further information about data processing can be found in the privacy policy at [https://www.surveymonkey.de/mp/legal/privacy/](https://www.surveymonkey.de/mp/legal/privacy/)

The provider processes your personal data on our behalf. The data processing in this context is based on our legitimate interest in increasing the attractiveness of our website, understanding Customer requirements, and improving target group-specific marketing.

#### 4\. Newsletter

We use your personal data to send you our newsletters and to inform you about news from our company, new services, new products, and events tailored to your interests. This includes information on current or future range of services and products as well as functions and events with participation of our company or group companies (e.g. trade fairs). To send you the newsletter, we need your e-mail address. The legal basis for the processing is your consent. We will use the personal data you provided during registration exclusively for sending our newsletter. After the registration of your e-mail address, you will receive an e-mail from us asking for you to confirm that you wish to receive the newsletter by clicking a link. If the confirmation by hyperlink is not given within a period of 7 days, your information will be blocked and deleted after a month. We are also entitled to keep your IP addresses, and times of registration and confirmation times to verify your registration and to appropriately clarify any possible misuse of your personal data.

We can analyse our newsletter campaigns. When you open an e-mail, a file contained in the e-mail (so-called web-beacon) connects to our newsletter-server. This makes it possible to determine whether a newsletter message has been opened and which links, if any, have been clicked on. In addition, technical information is recorded (e.g. time of retrieval, IP address, browser type and operating system). This information cannot be assigned to the respective newsletter recipient. It is used exclusively for the statistical analysis of newsletter campaigns. The results of these analyses can be used to better adapt future newsletters to the interests of the recipients. If you do not want any analysis, you must unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a corresponding link in every newsletter message.

The legal basis for this is your consent and the necessity for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject. The legal basis for the transfer to a third country is as well your consent. Please note that the level of EU data protection cannot be guaranteed in the third country. In particular, effective legal remedies against official access to your personal data may not exist.

Your data will be processed in an electronic newsletter system for the duration of your subscription. For this purpose and for sending the newsletter, we use the processor "HubSpot" of the provider HubSpot Ireland Ltd, One Dockland Central, Guild Street, Dublin 1, Co. Dublin, Ireland (US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA), which processes the data on our behalf.

If personal data is transferred to the US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA, HubSpot guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses plus UK Data Transfer Addendum to maintain EU and UK data protection level. For more information, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/security](https://legal.hubspot.com/security). For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

Since we base our processing on your consent, this means that you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time or to object to the processing of your personal data for the purpose of sending the newsletter. If you do so, we will immediately remove you from our newsletter distribution list to comply with your request. You can withdraw your consent at any time by sending an e-mail to our data protection officer or by following the instructions at the end of a promotional/newsletter e-mail. If you send us an e-mail, please let us know what your withdrawal should refer to so that we can assign your request.

#### 5\. Commercial Services

##### a. Account Registration

You may register a customer account. Registration of domain names is only possible if you have a registered account. You will need to provide some personal data during the registration process, which is marked with "mandatory field". These are generally the following categories of data:

Contact Name (First Name, Last Name), Address, City, Zip Code, Country, Phone number, E-Mail address

We will use this data for identification of customers and to administer your account. Additionally, the data will be used to pre-fill your domain name registration forms when you register an account. The legal basis for the data processing is the necessity to process personal data for the fulfilment of a contract or to process operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures.

Additionally, you may voluntarily provide further categories of data. This data will be processed for our legitimate interest of additional verification and quicker communication.

Furthermore, you will choose a User-ID and a password to log into your account. Please make sure that no unauthorised person gets access to the log-in credentials for your account.

A registered account is necessary to register domain names. For the processing of your personal data for domain name registrations, please refer to our Domain Name Registration Privacy Policy [https://iwantmyname.com/terms#use-personal-information](https://iwantmyname.com/terms#use-personal-information).

##### b. Log-In Using Third-Party Providers

As an alternative to registration, you can also log in using third-party services. An additional registration on our website is therefore not necessary. This requires that you are already registered with the third-party provider. For this purpose, you will find the corresponding icons of the respective providers of the social networks supported by our website on the registration page or login page. To log in, you will be redirected to the page of the third-party provider. There you can enter your credentials for registration. In this way, your profile data will be partially transmitted to us by the third-party provider. You can find out which information is transmitted to us in the privacy policy of the third-party provider. We do not obtain your password used with the third-party provider.

Only your name and e-mail address from this data will be collected by us to be able to assign and identify you in our system. This data will be combined with the data listed above under d.

The legal basis for the use of the services of the third-party providers is our legitimate interest in increasing the convenience of using our website.

We use the following services. In the linked privacy policy you will find more information about the privacy assessment of our cooperation. In addition, you will learn how you can assert your rights against the third-party provider.

* Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland.

    [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#applications](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#applications)
    
* Google Ireland Limited Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

* Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA.

* LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Attn: Legal Dept. (Privacy Policy and User Agreement), Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland.
    
    [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=homepage-basic\_footer-privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=homepage-basic_footer-privacy-policy)
    
* Github Inc., 88 Colin P Kelly Jr. Street, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA
    
    [https://docs.github.com/en/github/site-policy/github-privacy-statement](https://docs.github.com/en/github/site-policy/github-privacy-statement)

* Yahoo, Verizon Media EMEA Limited (Address: 5-7 Point Square, North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland).
    
    [https://www.verizonmedia.com/policies/ie/en/verizonmedia/terms/otos/index.html](https://www.verizonmedia.com/policies/ie/en/verizonmedia/terms/otos/index.html)

##### c. Payment

We use various payment methods from third party payment providers. If you choose one of these payment methods, your payment data will be forwarded to the respective payment service provider for payment processing. These third-party providers process your personal data as an independent controller according to their privacy terms. The transfer is based on the fulfilment of the contract and on our legitimate interests in secure payment processing and fraud prevention.

Please refer to the Terms and Conditions, Terms of Use and Privacy Policy of the respective payment provider.

* PayPal (Europe) S.a.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg.
    
    [https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en\_DE](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_DE)
    
* Alipay (Europe) Limited S.A., 11-13, Boulevard de la Foire, L – 1528, Luxembourg.

    [https://render.alipay.com/p/f/agreementpages/alipayglobalprivacypolicy.html](https://render.alipay.com/p/f/agreementpages/alipayglobalprivacypolicy.html)
    
* Union Pay International Co., Ltd., German Branch, An der Welle 4, 60322 Frankfurt.

* Skrill by Paysafe Group, Paysafe, Floor 27, 25 Canada Square, London, E14 5LQ.

* Worldpay by Fis.

When selecting the payment methods purchase on account and instalment purchase, in particular the following personal data is processed by us or our payment service provider as a controller for the purpose of payment processing and in this context for identity and credit checks:

* Contact and identification information: name, date of birth, national identification number, title, billing and delivery address, e-mail address, mobile phone number; nationality, salary, etc.
* Payment information: debit and credit card data (card number, expiry date and the CVV check digit), account number, etc.
* Information about the processing of the order, such as product type, product number, price, etc.

In the event that the payment method "purchase on account" or "instalment purchase" is selected, we or our payment service provider may process personal data and information about the user's previous payment history as well as probability values for the user's payment history in the future (so-called scoring) in order to decide whether the payment method can be offered to the user. The scoring is calculated on the basis of scientifically recognised mathematical-statistical methods.

##### d. Direct Marketing

We have a legitimate interest (direct advertising) in advertising customers (persons with whom we have had a business relationship) by e-mail or post. In particular, we may send you news about our company or group companies, information on events and invitations to review our services and products.

For this purpose and for sending the newsletter, we use the processor “HubSpot“ HubSpot Ireland Ltd, One Dockland Central, Guild Street, Dublin 1, Co. Dublin, Ireland (US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA), which processes data on our instructions.

If personal data is transferred to the US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA, HubSpot guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses plus UK Data Transfer Addendum to maintain EU and UK data protection level. For more information, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/security](https://legal.hubspot.com/security). For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

To send you advertising by post, we use a post service partner.

You can object to the sending of advertising at any time by sending an e-mail to our data protection officer or by following the instructions at the end of a promotional e-mail. If possible, please send your e-mail from the same e-mail address you used for registration, so that we can assign you more easily.

##### e. Domain Query (Whois)

We offer the possibility to obtain information about certain owner data of already registered domain names. In the event of a search query, the data you enter into the search field and the categories of data listed under “log files” are processed. The legal basis for the processing is the necessity to process personal data for the fulfilment of a contract or to process operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures in connection with the domain guidelines. Search requests are deleted no later than seven days after the request.

#### 6\. Contact, Live Chat

You can contact us by e-mail, postal or per live chat to request a quote or to conduct other correspondence.

In order to process your request, we process names, e-mail addresses, possibly the names of your company, position, mandatory information, which are absolutely necessary to create an offer. The processing of your data in the context of contact made by e-mail, a contact form or by telephone takes place on the basis of our legitimate interest to provide a good customer service or is necessary to fulfil a contract or to process operations necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures insofar as the contacts are related to contractual performance obligations such as the request of a dispute entry.

Contacting us for abuse and complaint messages requires users to log into their account. In addition, the categories of data listed in “log files” are processed. If you want to request a dispute entry, we also need your further contact details (last name, first name, address, name of the company) as well as a description of your request, stating the domain in question.

We will delete your contact requests immediately after processing unless statutory retention periods require continued retention. After answering your inquiry, we will archive your request immediately. Access is only possible to a very limited extent. Solely informative inquiries, i.e. which do not result in a contract or do not contain any other content that needs to be retained, will be deleted at the end of the year in which the request was made. See "Retention periods" for more information.

We use a ticket management system to process customer claims and inquiries by e-mail and via the contact forms. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interest in the efficient processing of requests.

When you use our contact form, we also process data about your location (country and city based on IP address), data obtained from our tracking system, and data about the browser and device used. We use the "HubSpot" service of the provider HubSpot Ireland Ltd, One Dockland Central, Guild Street, Dublin 1, Co. Dublin, Ireland (US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA) as part of the contact form. For this purpose, we have concluded a data processing agreement with HubSpot, in which HubSpot undertakes to process data only in accordance with our instructions. We process your data based on our legitimate interests (efficient processing of requests).

As soon as the contact form is filled out, this information is linked to HubSpot's tracking information if you have consented to this in the cookie settings at the outset. If the email address filled in the form can be linked to an existing contact, we can identify you as an existing contact. The legal basis is your consent, which can be given when you first visit the website. You can withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future via the cookie settings.

Insofar as personal data is transferred to the US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA, HubSpot guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses plus UK Data Transfer Addendum to maintain EU and UK data protection level. For more information, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/security](https://legal.hubspot.com/security). For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

Your inquiry and your contact data may be stored in a customer relationship management system ("CRM system") if a business relationship exists or if a business initiation can be expected on the basis of prior communication. We use the CRM system "HubSpot" of the provider HubSpot Ireland Ltd, One Dockland Central, Guild Street, Dublin 1, Co. Dublin, Ireland (US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA). For this purpose, we have concluded a data processing agreement with HubSpot, in which HubSpot undertakes to process user data only in accordance with our instructions. We process your data based on our legitimate economic interests in being able to systematically manage customer and potential customer contact data. In the case of personal data in the CRM system, a check is made after two years at the end of the respective calendar year to determine whether further storage is necessary. If there is no need to do so or if there are no further legal retention obligations, the data will be deleted. If personal data is transferred to the US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA, HubSpot guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses plus UK Data Transfer Addendum to maintain EU and UK data protection level. For more information, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/security](https://legal.hubspot.com/security). For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy). We use a ticket management system to process customer claims and inquiries by e-mail. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interest in the efficient processing of requests.

For using our live chat, we process your name, and you e-mail address of your registered account. We use Zendesk Inc, 1019 Market Street, San Francisco, CA 94103. Further information can be found at [https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/eu-data-protection/](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/eu-data-protection/).

C. Statistics, Web-Analytics, Advertising based on Tracking and Retargeting – Use of Cookies
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

In some cases, we or our partners use cookies or process your data in such a way that your consent is required. Cookies are small text files that can be stored on your device when you visit our website. Tracking is possible using various technologies like the pixel technology or log file analysis. Consent is given via the so-called cookie banner, which must be actively clicked. Our cookie policy explains how you can disable individual functions to which you have consented. There you will find information on when cookies expire, how to delete cookies and how to withdraw your consent.

Unless otherwise stated, the processing described in this section is based on your consent. Learn more about how to withdraw your consent in our cookie policy [https://internetbs.net/en/cookiepolicy.html](https://internetbs.net/en/cookiepolicy.html).

#### 1\. Web-Analytics, Statistics

To determine which content from our website is most interesting for you we continuously measure the number of visitors and the most viewed content. Therefore, we process your personal data,

* to record the number of visitors of our websites,
* to record the respective visiting times of our website visitors and
* to record the sequence of visits to different websites and product sites to optimise our website.

##### a. Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics of Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (Holding Company: Google LLC 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) to analyse the usage of our web services. The collected data is used to optimise our website and our advertising effort.

Google Analytics is a web-analysing-service provided by Google. Google processed this data on our behalf and is contractually bound to implicate measures to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of the data.

Upon visiting our website, the following data is processed:

* IP-address (in a shortened form. User cannot be directly identified)
* Approximate location (country and city)
* Technical information like browser, internet provider, device and screen resolution
* User behaviour (accessed pages, clicks and scroll-behaviour)
* Orders including the revenue of the ordered products
* Origin of your visit (from which website or which advertisement our site was reached)
* Session length and if the site was left without any interaction
* Adding to favourites
* Sharing of content (social media)

The legal basis is your consent. Upon the first visit to our website, we ask for your consent. Consent may be withdrawn at any time. This can be done here (link to Cookie-Settings of the website) or by deleting the cookies in your browser. Another possibility is the browser addon provided by google, which deactivates Google Analytics. You can download it here:

[https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=dehttps://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=dehttps://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de)

Insofar as Google Ireland Limited transfers personal data to the US parent company Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, Google guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses to maintain the EU level of data protection.

Google Analytics sets cookies in your browser for the duration of two years from your last visit. These cookies contain a randomly generated User-ID, with which you can be recognised upon your next visit. The recorded data is stored in combination with the randomly generated User-ID, which makes an analysis of pseudonymised user profiles possible. This data will be automatically deleted after 14 months. Other data is stored in aggregated form indefinitely.

##### b. Hotjar

This website uses Hotjar (Service Provider: Hotjar Ltd, St Julians Business Centre, Elia Zammit Street 3, St Julians STJ 3155, Malta, Europa), to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise this service and experience.

Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users’ experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback.

Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour and their devices. This includes a device's IP address (processed during your session and stored in a de-identified form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), and the preferred language used to display our website. Hotjar stores this information on our behalf in a pseudonymised user profile. Hotjar is contractually forbidden to sell any of the data collected on our behalf.

The legal basis is your consent. Upon the first visit to our website, we ask for your consent. Consent may be withdrawn at any time. This can be done here (link to Cookie-Settings of the website) or by deleting the cookies in your browser.

According to Hotjar, the data will only be retained for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it or as required by law. Hotjar is contractually forbidden to sell any of the data collected on our behalf.

For further details, please see [https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy/](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy/).

##### c. HubSpot

We use the HubSpot service of the provider HubSpot Ireland Ltd, One Dockland Central, Guild Street, Dublin 1, Co. Dublin, Ireland (US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA) on this website to analyze the use of our website and for tracking/marketing measures/usage behavior in order to provide you with advertising that really interests you. For analysis purposes and as part of the optimization of our marketing measures, the following data may be collected and processed via HubSpot:

* Geographic position
* Browser type
* Navigation information
* Referral URL
* Performance data
* HubSpot subscription service credentials
* Files that are displayed on site
* Domain names
* Pages viewed
* Aggregated usage
* Operating system version
* Internet service provider
* IP address
* Device identifier
* Duration of visit
* Operating system
* Events that occur via website
* Access times
* Clickstream data
* Device model and version

For the purpose of web analysis, so-called "web beacons" are used and also "cookies" are set, which are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of the website by us. For more information about Hubspot's use of cookies, please visit [https://knowledge.hubspot.com/reports/what-cookies-does-hubspot-set-in-a-visitor-s-browser](https://knowledge.hubspot.com/reports/what-cookies-does-hubspot-set-in-a-visitor-s-browser).

The legal basis for the processing is your consent, which can be withdrawn at any time with effect for the future, which you have given via the cookie settings. You can withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future via the cookie settings.

Insofar as personal data is transferred to the US parent company HubSpot, Inc., 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141 USA, HubSpot guarantees by means of standard contractual clauses plus UK Data Transfer Addendum to maintain EU and UK data protection level. For more information, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/security](https://legal.hubspot.com/security). For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please visit [https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

#### 2\. Advertising based on Tracking and Retargeting

We would like to show you - also on the websites of our advertising partners - only advertising that really interests you. Therefore, we use the technologies of so-called tracking and retargeting on our website for advertising that is tailored to your interests. Cookies are usually used for this purpose, but other technologies such as so-called "fingerprinting" are also used in some cases. The cookies temporarily stored for this purpose enable our retargeting partners to recognise visitors to our website under a pseudonym and to display only products that are likely to interest you. Fingerprinting recognizes your device based on your computer hardware, software, add-ons and browser settings.

Unless otherwise stated, the processing described in this section is based on your consent. Learn more about how to withdraw your consent in our cookie policy [https://internetbs.net/en/cookiepolicy.html](https://internetbs.net/en/cookiepolicy.html). There you will find information on when cookies expire and how to delete cookies.

In detail, we use the data collected for statistical and advertising purposes

* for targeted advertising, also via advertising networks in cooperation with partners,
* to measure the success and billing of advertising measures between advertising partners and us,
* to keep track of what ads you have already seen to prevent you from seeing the same one again and
* to assess which parts of our website need to be optimised.

Unless otherwise stated, we use the following services as processors and contractually oblige them to process data only on our behalf.

##### a. Facebook Pixel

Facebook Pixel is a service of Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. The service enables us to determine target groups for advertisements on Facebook, so-called "Facebook Ads", based on website visits and surfing behaviour. We also use this pixel to measure the effectiveness of online marketing measures. In this way, we can track the actions of users after they have seen a Facebook Ad and/or clicked and then placed an order. When you visit a website, the pixel is integrated directly by Facebook and can store a cookie on your device. If you subsequently log in to Facebook or are already logged in to Facebook, your visit to this site will be logged in your profile. The collected user data is anonymous for us and therefore does not allow us to draw any conclusions about your identity. However, this data is stored and processed by Facebook so that it is possible to draw conclusions about the respective user profile. Data processing by Facebook is carried out according to the Facebook data usage guidelines. For this purpose, we have concluded a joint controller arrangement with Facebook. For more information about Facebook's data processing, please visit: [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

This could take a few seconds.  
Here are some domaining fun facts while you wait:

The Domain Name System (DNS) was created in 1983 by Paul Mockapetris, an American computer scientist. This system replaced the prior method of identifying computers on a network, which was a simple text file.

The first domain name ever registered was "symbolics.com" on March 15, 1985. It was registered by the Symbolics Computer Corporation, a computer manufacturer.

Domain names can be up to 63 characters long, not including the domain extension (.com, .org, .net, etc.) and the total URL can be up to 255 characters long.

Domain names were initially limited to ASCII characters, but with the introduction of Internationalized Domain Names (IDNs) in the late 1990s, domain names could include characters from non-Latin scripts.

DNS propagation is the time it takes for all DNS servers worldwide to update their records with new DNS information. This can take anywhere from a few hours to a few days.

The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) is responsible for managing and coordinating the DNS to ensure that every domain name links to the correct IP address.

ICANN introduced new generic top-level domains (gTLDs) in 2011, providing more options beyond .com, .org, etc. Examples include .app, .music, .blog, and many others. A further round of new gTLDs is predicted in 2026.

Mike Mann, founder of BuyDomains and DomainMarket, reportedly owns one of the largest private domain name portfolios in the world. He is famous for once registering nearly 15,000 domain names in a single day.

Known as the "Domain King," Rick Schwartz has made a fortune by buying and selling domain names. He sold "Porno.com" for $8.9 million in 2015, one of the highest prices ever paid for a domain name.

Frank Schilling is a notable domain investor who started in the early 2000s. His company, Uniregistry, was one of the biggest winners in ICANN's new gTLD program, securing rights to run extensions like .link and .sexy.

Chris Chena started buying domains in the late '90s. One of his notable sales includes the domain "shop.com" which sold for around $3.5 million.

Yun Ye, a relatively secretive domain investor, amassed a huge portfolio of premium .com domains. He made headlines in 2004 when he sold his portfolio of about 100,000 domains to Marchex for $164 million.

Michael Berkens co-founded WorldWide Media, which had a portfolio of more than 75,000 domain names. One of his most notable sales was "meet.me" which sold for $450,000.

Andrew Rosener is the CEO of MediaOptions, a domain brokerage firm. He has brokered some of the industry's largest domain name sales, such as "x.com" to Elon Musk.

Ali Zandi is a well-known domain investor who has had success both in buying and selling domains. He sold the domain "Freedom.com" for $2 million in 2017.

Unknown

Unknown

Pending

Available

Invalid

Not available

Reserved

Preorder

Not supported 

Not supported 

Remove from cart

View Cart

Loading

Add to cart

Filter TLDs Include Premiums Available Only Exact Match

A - E F - J K - N O - R S - Z Show All

ai asia auto art audio autos au at associates apartments airforce accountants app ae.org africa.com auction army agency actor academy ac.nz ac accountant adult ae aero africa ag am as attorney biz be bz biz.pl beauty boats baby bargains builders build boston bingo best business br.com bar bid band bike boutique beer berlin bet bi bio black blog blue broker buzz com co.uk ch cx co cz college cars com.pl com.bz co.bz car club cool cc co.in com.de com.co christmas cymru charity ceo catering casa careers cards capetown claims cleaning com.au cologne co.za clothing clinic click camp camera cab ca condos community construction cruises cricket co.com company center com.se cn.com care city codes coach coffee cheap chat casino cash church capital cafe consulting contractors credit coupons computer com.mx com.pk com.cm cm co.cm co.nz cam career cat cl cloud club.tw co.at co.gg co.je co.nl co.no com.ag com.ai com.ar com.es com.gl com.hn com.lc com.nf com.ng com.pe com.ph com.sc com.tw com.vc com.vn compare contact cooking country courses creditcard de diet dental diamonds day dev desi durban democrat degree deals dentist digital domains design de.com download date discount dog delivery dating dance doctor directory direct dk dm eu edu.pl es exposed equipment education email eu.com expert express exchange events estate enterprises engineering engineer energy earth ebiz.tw ec eco

fr fans flowers florist football fun futbol furniture fail faith fi fan foundation firm.in family farm fyi fund forsale flights financial finance fitness fm fo fashion film fish fit forex gay global gr gb.net guru game guitars gifts glass gmbh gdn gripe ga graphics gratis guide group gallery gr.com gen.in gives gold golf games geek.nz gen.nz garden gd gg gift gl green gs gy hosting hair homes healthcare hockey holdings holiday hospital host house hu.net haus health help hiphop hiv hn horse how ht it io info in info.pl icu immo immobilien insure industries in.net ink ind.in institute international investments irish im inc is isla.pr istanbul joburg jewelry jetzt jp.net jpn.com jp je jobs

kaufen koeln kitchen kim kiwi li lt lu la life lat lol lease limo limited lighting legal link lv luxury loans london love land loan live ltd lawyer lc llc law me mobi mom makeup motorcycles memorial mortgage menu men markets maison me.uk media money management mex.com market marketing mba moda movie mx maori.nz monster md mg miami mn moe ms mu museum net nl net.pl net.bz nagoya navy net.au net.co net.in nom.co nyc nom.fr network news ninja net.cm net.pk net.nz net.ag net.gg net.je net.pe net.sc new ng nu nz

online org org.uk observer org.pl org.bz one okinawa onl org.in org.mx org.nz org.pk org.ag org.es org.gg org.il org.je org.sc organic pl pro pw protection pm pics page party pictures plumbing photography photos press pub pizza partners parts properties productions plus pk pe pet ph photo pink poker porn pr promo property ps quest qpon re ro realty ryukyu republican reisen reise rehab racing rodeo rip rent review ru.com rest restaurant report reviews rocks run repair rentals recipes radio radio.am radio.fm red rugby

store site si space storage skin school sarl saarland salon schule singles se shoes sk supplies stream surgery supply srl solar soccer solutions systems services shop sa.com science se.net security studio sale shopping show social software style support sx sc scot sex sexy sh ski so spa sucks tech tv tf tickets tel tools today tax tires tennis theater tienda tube tips technology trade tokyo theatre training taxi team tours town toys tm tc tl top trading travel tw us uk us.com us.org uk.com uno uk.net university uz villas vip voyage vacations viajes video vision vegas ventures vet vin vg vc vn vote website wf work win wales wang works watch wiki webcam wine world wtf ws wedding wien xyz xn--qxa6a xn--e1a4c xn--5tzm5g xn--6frz82g xn--c1avg xn--q9jyb4c xn--t60b56a xn--tckwe xn--unup4y xn--vhquv xn--nqv7f xn--ngbc5azd xn--czrs0t xn--fjq720a xn--i1b6b1a6a2e xn--mk1bu44c xn--80asehdb xn--80aswg xn--9dbq2a yt yachts yokohama yoga zone za.bz za.com

[Add all](javascript:void(0);)

[Add](javascript:void(0);)

\[\[idn\]\]

\[\[discount\]\]\[\[price\]\] \[\[period\_tag\]\]

Renews at \[\[renewalPrice\]\]/\[\[renewal\_period\_tag\]\]

\[\[tld\]\]

 Add to cart

Include Numbers Include IDNS Include Dashes    Max Characters     25      Apply Filters

* * *

Load more suggestions

\[\[domain\]\] [Add to cart](javascript:void(0))

There are no more domains we can suggest, please try another search query.

Whois Details
-------------

##### \[\[domain\]\]

* * *

##### Whois Data

**Registration Date**: \[\[CREATION\]\]  
**Expiration Date**: \[\[EXPIRY\]\]  
**Status**:

\[\[STATUS\]\]

##### Nameservers

\[\[NSLIST\]\]

\[\[WHOIS\]\]

* * *

View Full Whois Data 

### Need help?

Questions or concerns? Let us know!

[Live Chat](javascript:%24zopim.livechat.window.show(); "Live Chat")

Get Instant First Class Support

* * *

* **ICANN Policies**

* **Quick Links**

* **We accept**
* 

* * *

© Internet Domain Service BS Corp. 2015 — 2024

This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms of Service](https://policies.google.com/terms) apply.

Page Loading. Please wait... en cba9103d2bc0ec6ce5f59c0192b96c2db7046dc6-1733926969-f23721a9e653b99540dd5276d818af2c
